这录音室真不错
This is a really nice room.
那是 声音够浑厚  可惜请不到他
Yeah, it sounds thick. Too bad he's not coming.
-我亲口跟他谈的  他会来的  -是啊
- Look, I talked to him myself. He'll be here.  - Right.
是你说要加段小号和声
You're the one who said that the song
我才请来独一无二的约翰·亨利
could use a horn part, so I got the best-- John Henry.
-得了吧你  -真的  不过不重要
- You think I'm stupid?  - Of course I do, but that's not the point.
他一定会来的  好吧
He'll be here, okay?
左转直走
Take a left up ahead.
去南街吗  那通告我取消了
South Street? I canceled this gig.
你说这阵子不想接任何通告的
You said you didn't want to do any sessions for a while.
那是前阵子  我电话联系过  接下了
For a while. I called her. I uncanceled it.
-能应付吗  -试试就知道
- Are you up to it?  - Let's find out.
你骗我
# You lied to me #
约翰·亨利决不会出现
# John Henry's never gonna show up ##
你有完没完
Will you stop?
-都等了两小时了  -那也得继续等
- It's been, like, two hours. - And we will keep waiting.
你听过他的演奏  知道他的境界
You've heard this guy play, and you know what he does,
能闭嘴了吧  汤米
so can you just shut up, Tommy?
-天哪  -我来晚了吗
- Oh, my God.  - Am I late?
-需要再听一遍吗  -不用  可以了
- You need to hear it again?   - Nope. I get it.
试一遍吧  看看效果  开始吧
Let's try one. See what we get. Let's do it.
约翰  你没事吧
John! You okay?
-你没事吧  -我喘不过气来  喘不过气
- You okay?  - I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
叫救护车
Call an ambulance!
快
Now!
我要入伙
I want in.
约翰·亨利·贾尔斯吗  你是他乐迷?
John Henry Giles? You a fan of his music?
他是音乐人?
He's a musician?
瘫痪嘛  两年都不良于行
That paralysis thing-- Guy can't walk for two years.
一直无法确诊  有点儿意思
Nobody knows why. It seems mildly interesting.
别提他的瘫痪
Forget his paralysis.
这话你该对他保龄球队球友说
Tell that to the rest of his bowling team.
就本院而言
As far as this hospital is concerned,
只是例单纯大叶性肺炎  没难度的
this is a simple case of lobar pneumonia. Boring.
但他的瘫痪
But that not-walking thing
真可能会有严重后果
That could turn into something serious.
加州的马蒂·汉密尔顿  才是他的主治医师
Marty Hamilton is his primary physician out in California.
他在治疗病人的瘫痪
He's dealing with the paralysis.
我懂  治疗复治疗  手术再手术
Know all about it. Multiple treatments, multiple surgeries--
他一直都在好转  除了他的腿  包治百病
He's making real progress. Fixed everything but the legs.
汉密尔顿医生已经打过电话  请你们小组帮忙
Dr. Hamilton already called and asked for your team.
是你们小组  不是你
And by team, I don't mean you.
我知道  团队里不能有自我意识
Like I always say, there's no "I" In team.
即使有我  也不能喧宾夺主
There is a "Me" though, if you jumble it up.
福曼实习期间跟过汉密尔顿
Foreman did his residency with Hamilton.
我知道  聘用他前我瞄过一眼简历
I know. I accidentally glanced at his resume before I hired him.
他要找自己信得过的人
He wants someone he can trust.
他肯定找福曼的假释官谈过了
He must've spoken to Foreman's parole officer.
一个可以单纯治疗肺炎的医生
Someone who will stick to the pneumonia.
约翰·亨利的瘫痪治疗尚在论证阶段
John Henry's on an experimental protocol for the paralysis.
-我尊重他的意见  我不会乱插一脚的  -福曼负责这病人
- I respect that. I'm not gonna get in his way. - It's Foreman's case.
就治个肺炎  他能行的
It's pneumonia. He can handle it.
都瘫痪了  也坏不到哪儿去了
Guy's already paralyzed. How badly can he screw it up?
那么
So,
-血氧浓度多少  -插鼻管后维持在90
- What are his SATs? - Staying in the 90s on the nasal cannula.
-咳嗽有痰吗  -几乎没有  情况稳定
- Coughing up sputum? - Almost none. He seems stabilized.
豪斯医生  小动作给您启发了吗
Dr. House, is there anything back from micro?
还没  要炒我吗
Not yet. You gonna fire me?
-帮我洗洗车  这事儿就过去了  -挺冷的
- You can make up for it by washing my car. - Oh, this is fun.
好了  继续给他用广谱抗生素
Okay. Let's keep him on the broad-spectrum antibiotics.
既然他有感染症状
And since he's displaying septic physiology,
给他抽血做肾上腺和甲状腺功能检测
draw blood for adrenal and thyroid function.
-那瘫痪呢  -咱们只负责治疗肺炎
- What about the paralysis? - We're sticking to the pneumonia.
当然  老大
Well, you certainly are, boss,
您可是一言既出  八匹马也难追
like a wet tongue sticks to dry ice.
汉密尔顿医生已经确诊了他的瘫痪
The paralysis has already been diagnosed by Dr. Hamilton.
-是肌萎缩性脊髓侧索硬化症  -路格里克氏病
- It's A.L.S. - Lou Gehrig's disease.
诊断过程很有趣  还拍了部电影的
It's a lovely diagnosis. They make movies about it.
未作检测谈何治疗  只能用排除法确诊
No tests, no treatment-- It's a disease of exclusion.
-汉密尔顿已经排除了其他任何可能  -我没有
- Because Hamilton has excluded everything else. - I haven't.
还可能是什么呢
What else could it be?
-格林-巴利综合症  病程是可逆的  -很好
- Guillain-Barr? Which would be reversible. - Excellent.
不对  那瘫痪应该是对称恶化的  他的不是
No. The progression of the paralysis would be symmetric. His wasn't.
-横贯性脊髓炎  -汉密尔顿检测过了  阴性
- Transverse myelitis. - Hamilton tested for it. Negative.
同时否定了恶性肿瘤和动静脉畸型
And he was negative for Masses and A.V.M.
抗体可能正在破坏神经系统
Antibodies could be attacking the nerves.
-多灶性运动神经症  -不常见  但症状相符
- Multifocal motor neuropathy. - Uncommon, but it fits.
也是可治愈的
It's also treatable.
汉密尔顿试过用免疫球蛋白治疗吗
Did Hamilton try putting the guy on I.V.I.G.?
没有  因为核磁共振结果显示...
No, because the M.R.I. Showed no--
那就再做一次
Well, let's do an M.R.I. of our own.
各位  这是我的病人
Guys, it's my case.
症状与A.L.S.相符  肺炎也正是其并发症之一
A.L.S. Fits. It even predicts the pneumonia.
说明瘫痪症状在恶化
The paralysis is progressive.
-这可是不治之症  -但这并不意味着是误诊
- It's a death sentence. - That doesn't make it wrong.
你觉得呼吸衰竭是A.L.S.引发的吗
So you think the breathing stuff is connected to my A.L.S.?
有这种可能
It makes sense.
病情恶化了  是吗
So it's just gonna get worse, huh?
-汉密尔顿医生他...  -他人不错
- Well, Dr. Hamilton... - Great guy.
是位好医生  但显然他的治疗不起作用
Really smart doctor, and his treatment obviously isn't working.
你觉得我会死在这里
Do you think I'm gonna die here,
还是能先回趟家
or you think I get to go back home first?
核磁共振能让我们更好了解病情...
An M.R.I. would give us a better idea...
核磁共振  拜托  这只是肺炎
An M.R.I. Come on. For pneumonia?
-豪斯医生认为该考虑其他...  -豪斯
- Dr. House thinks we should test for other... - House?
听说过  那个有强迫症的混蛋
Yeah, I heard about him. Obsessive son of a bitch?
正是
That's him.
你赞同谁  汉密尔顿还是豪斯
So who do you think is right, Hamilton or House?
两位都是杰出的内科医生
Hey, they're both excellent physicians.
少来了
Come on.
一个说是A.L.S  另一个说不是
One of 'em says A.L.S. The other one says not A.L.S.
非此即彼  小子
You gotta pick one, son.
症状显示是A.L.S
Everything points to A.L.S.
那就不做核磁共振
Then no M.R.I.
我想签署份文件
And I want one of them papers that say,
一旦病情恶化  就放弃治疗
I don't want nothing done if something go bad.
签D.N.R吗  贾尔斯先生  不必这么仓促决定...
A D.N.R.? Mr. Giles, you don't want to rush into--
已经两年了  不仓促  我心意已决
It's been two years. I ain't rushin'. I want to sign one.
现在就签
Now.
趁我的胳膊还能动
While my arm still works.
他签了D.N.R.协议
He signed a D.N.R.
他用晚餐写了一首歌
He rhymes with dinner?
他签了D.N.R.协议
He signed a D.N.R.
这话听着通多了
That makes more sense.
-你跟他说了  可能不是A.L.S.吗  -没有
- You tell him it might not be A.L.S.? - No.
怪不得他会签  谁不会呢
Well, no wonder he signed. Who wouldn't?
开始给他静脉滴注类固醇和甲状腺素
I started him on I.V. Steroids and Synthroid.
很好  如果是我的病人
Great. If it was my case,
我还会给他加免疫球蛋白
I'd be adding a little I.V.I.G. to the mix.
-治肺炎吗  -我的病人  我说了算
- For his pneumonia? - That's my story, and I'm sticking to it.
他不想再做什么检测  放弃治疗了
He doesn't want anything done. No treatment.
D.N.R.是指不予抢救  不是不予治疗
D.N.R. Means "Do not resuscitate", not "Do not treat".
什么都不做  我俩谁对都没有意义
You do nothing, doesn't matter which one of us is right.
那份D.N.R.可保存好了
And hang on to that D.N.R.
他的签名很快就会值一大笔钱
That signature could be worth a lot of money real soon.
我是福曼医生  贾尔斯先生情况如何
This is Dr. Foreman. What is Mr. Giles's status?
好  类固醇用量增加到每12小时100毫克  还有...
Okay. Increase the steroids to 100 milligrams every 12 hours and, uh--
开始注射免疫球蛋白
start him on I.V.I.G.
对  我确定  剂量为体重的千分之一
Yeah. Yeah, I'm sure. One gram per kilo.
我最近雄风不再
My nature isn't what it used to be.
小家伙最近有点力不从心
The little man has lost some bounce in his step.
他要好好发动发动  周末出去找点乐子
He needs to crank it up, have himself some fun this weekend.
他想来几颗蓝色的小药丸
He wants the blue pills.
你在用第三人称称呼你的老二
You're taking about your penis in the third person.
我和他  完全两个人
Me and him-- two people.
各行其事吗  确实有必要用药
Separate vacations? That'd be a drag for one of you.
但不是蓝色小药丸
I don't think you need the pills.
你用药有问题
I think you have a conflict in medications.
需要把胰岛素用量
You need to up your insulin
-增加到吃巧克力冰激凌一样多  -胰岛素?
- to chocolate chip ice-cream levels. - Insulin?
对  你知道的  糖尿病人该吃的那种
Yeah. You remember. That's the stuff you take for the diabetes...
而你显然忘记跟护士说这病史
that you forgot to tell the nurse about.
你的手
Your hands--
没有汗毛  说明神经损伤
No hair, which means nerve damage.
你的鞋子  起码小了两号
And your shoes look about two sizes too small,
说明你脚部已失去知觉
which means you've lost sensation in your feet.
然后还有你的裤子
And then there's your pants.
裤子告诉你我有糖尿病吗
My pants tell you I have diabetes?
不  说明你是个白痴
No. They tell me you're an idiot.
右边裤腿上有糖粉
Powdered sugar on the right pant leg.
加上你裤兜里那两张餐巾纸
Based on the two napkins in your pocket--
我敢说你今天已经吃了不止一个甜甜圈
I'd bet it's not your first doughnut of the day.
紧急抢救  约翰·亨利·贾尔斯  324病房
Code Blue: John Henry Giles RM 324
-你给我开伟哥了  -对  干嘛不开
- You're giving me the pills?  - Sure. Why not?
要是再不注意而引起了心脏病
If you've got heart disease
吃了这药你就死翘翘了
from ignoring the diabetes, they'll kill you.
注意点儿  你俩这周末就爽了
Otherwise, you two have a fun weekend.
血氧浓度在下降
O2 SATS are dropping.
-呼吸音如何  -粗糙
- Breath sounds? - Junky.
-粘液阻塞吗  -不  是我们的错
- Mucus plug? - No, it's our mistake.
免疫球蛋白引起血栓  导致肺部无法供血
Sludging from the I.V.I.G. Blood can't get to his lungs.
准备500毫升肝素  静脉滴注
Start heparin-- 500 C.C.'s I.V.
他撑不到肝素起作用
He won't last long enough for it to work.
必须立刻插喉管
We've got to intubate him stat.
不行  他签过D.N.R.
We can't. He's D.N.R.
什么
What?
-乐迷吧  -对
- Someone likes music. - Oh, yeah.
血氧浓度只有70
His SATS are in the 70s.
-有多久了  -10分钟
- How long's he been like this? - Ten minutes.
-干吗不...  -是免疫球蛋白导致呼吸衰竭
- Why aren't you-- - The I.V.I.G. Put him in respiratory failure.
-你给他加了免疫球蛋白  -是我们
- You put him on I.V.I.G.? - We did this.
那就取消  奇斯
So undo it. Chase?
太晚了  是我们害死了他
It's too late. We killed him.
没人害死他  他还没死呢
Nobody killed him. He's not dead.
-奇斯  插喉管  -他签了D.N.R.
- Chase, intubate him. - He's D.N.R.
你要干什么
What are you doin'?
不能这么做
You can't do this!
-气囊  -你不能这么做
- Bag. - You can't do this.
气囊
Bag!
他对某种用药有不良反应
He had a bad reaction to some medicine we gave him.
你刚刚做了什么
What did you just do?
他救了他一命
He saved his life.
使用呼吸机后情况稳定  吸氧充分
He's stable on the ventilator, oxygenating well.
免疫球蛋白致他病情恶化
The I.V.I.G. made him worse,
说明他的病不是多灶性运动神经症
which means multifocal motor neuropathy was a bad diagnosis.
好了  他到底是什么病
Okay, what's really wrong with him?
你有毛病是吧
What's wrong with you?
我有什么病地球人都知道
Everyone knows what's wrong with me.
知道他有什么病  才更有意思
What's wrong with him is more interesting.
你给放弃抢救的病人插喉管
You tubed him, and he didn't want to be tubed.
他可是签过法律文件的
He has a legal paper saying just that.
插喉管还是不插喉管
To intubate or not to intubate
那是个道德问题
That is the big ethical question.
事实上  我不希望讨论这个
Actually, I was hoping we could avoid it
还是直接考虑后续用药问题
and maybe just practice some medicine.
根本就没有问题  病人已经决定了
There is no question. It's the patient's decision.
那也得病人有能力决定
If the patient is competent to make it.
而不是因甲状腺水平造成情绪抑郁
If his thyroid numbers aren't making him sad.
天哪  你说这话谁信啊
Oh, my God. You don't believe that.
他的甲状腺水平确实有点儿低
His thyroid levels were a little...
这不代表什么  别帮他讲话
It's nothing. Do not defend him!
-他为何要签D.N.R.  -我可没有让他...
- Why did he sign that D.N.R.? - I-I didn't talk him into--
不  他签D.N.R.协议
No. He signed the D.N.R.
是因为不想因A.L.S.缓慢痛苦地死去
'cause he didn't want a slow, painful death from A.L.S.
可他刚才那种情况  跟A.L.S.完全无关
What was happening had nothing to do with his A.L.S.
完全正确  那是免疫球蛋白造成的
Exactly! It's the I.V.I.G.
是你用错药了
You screwed up!
你不想让他死  是因为你用错药了
You're not gonna let him die because you screwed up.
严格说来  你的病人  是你搞砸了
Technically, your case. You screwed up.
你这样算什么
Is that what this is about
让你前老大没面子吗
looking bad in front of your old boss?
-你给他造成了伤害  -好吧  我保证不再犯
- You assaulted that man. - Fine. I'll never do it again.
-谁信啊  -所以说这场争论完全没意义嘛
- Yes, you will. - All the more reason this debate is pointless.
肺部情况恶化  有何可能
His lungs are worse. Any theories?
我确信他没事的
Oh, I'm sure he just went
小男孩躲自己房间去而已  来想病因吧
to the little boys' room. Come on, people.
-结节性脉管炎  -不会两个肺都感染
- Um, vasculitis? - Wouldn't likely hit both lungs.
有可能是韦格纳肉芽肿
It could be Wegener's granulomatosis.
豪斯医生
Dr. House?
卡迪又给我找了个脱衣舞女
Cuddy sent me a stripper again?
爱死她了  这么周到
Love that woman. So thoughtful.
抱歉让你失望了
Sorry.
有过类似病例
There are case reports of
韦格纳肉芽肿同时感染双肺和脊柱
Wegener's hitting both the lungs and the spine.
那病也很凶险  但总比A.L.S.好
Well, it's not great, but it's better than A.L.S.
至少尚可治疗
At least it's treatable.
这是法院的禁制令
It's a restraining order.
禁止你出现在约翰·亨利·贾尔斯50英尺以内
You're not to come within 50 feet of John Henry Giles,
已上诉地方法院  控告你伤害罪
and they've asked the D.A. to file criminal charges for battery.
卡梅隆  检测血清  是否胞浆型阳性
Cameron, test the blood for C-ANCA.
这可是刑事指控
These are criminal charges.
不会允许你继续抽血化验的
They're not gonna let you take blood to make more tests.
实验室还有他血样  加一项包浆抗体检测就是
He has blood left in the lab. Just add on the C-ANCA.
福曼还要求你们做
Foreman still got you doing bronchoscopic
-肺部抽痰吗  -四小时一次
- suctioning for the pneumonia? - Every four hours.
好  窥镜探入肺部时
Well, while you're down in his lungs,
取点活组织做切片  得证实是否韦氏病
grab a biopsy. We'll need it to confirm Wegener's.
-还有  把他搬到二楼的重症监护室  -为什么
- And move the patient to the second floor I.C.U. - Why?
就在门诊部楼上
It's right above the clinic.
不管怎么算  都在50英尺以内
I'm pretty sure it's 50 feet in any direction.
能有法院禁令
It's nice having a court order
让我免了在门诊值班  挺好的
saying you don't have to work clinic duty.
-卡迪医生  -失陪一下
- Dr. Cuddy!  - Excuse me.
-你呼我  -你喊什么喊
- You paged me. - Why the yelling?
他的床位就在墙后面  原告
His bed is behind that wall-- the plaintiff's.
你知道的  我不能靠近他
I can't, you know, come any closer.
就在门诊部楼上  很聪明嘛
It's right over the clinic. Very cute.
说教能长话短说吗  我还得...
Can we get the lecture over with 'cause I've gotta--
事实上  我没事可做  你尽管说
Actually, I've got nothing to do. Take your time.
要帮你请律师吗
You need a lawyer?
你对我的所作所为  没意见吗
You don't have a problem with what I did?
我雇你的时候  就知道你是个疯子
When I hired you, I knew you were insane.
我将继续致力于阻止你疯狂行事
I will continue to try and stop you from doing insane things.
一旦事已酿成
But once they're done,
还执迷不悟的阻止你
trying to convince an insane person
那就是我有问题了
not to do insane things is in itself insane.
雇你的时候  就已经做了每年五万的预算
So when I hired you, I also set aside $50,000
为你找律师
a year for legal expenses.
目前为止  还能糊弄过来
So far you've come in under budget.
太好了  那还能帮我做些化验吗
Great. Any chance you could help me run some tests?
福曼医生打电话给汉密尔顿了
Dr. Foreman called Dr. Hamilton.
他正从洛杉矶飞来
He's flying in from L.A.
你可以跟他谈谈
You can talk to him.
汉密尔顿医生此次是以约翰·亨利朋友身份前来
Dr. Hamilton is flying in as a friend of John Henry's...
帮他放弃治疗的
to pull the plug.
对  我要个律师
Yeah. I need a lawyer.
法官大人  作为格利高里·豪斯的代理律师
Your Honor, on behalf of Gregory House,
要求法院紧急开庭是为提交诉讼请求
we have convened an emergency session of this court...
请求法院裁定
to bring a motion requesting
约翰·亨利·贾尔斯继续接受治疗
that John Henry Giles remain on life support.
豪斯医生被指控故意伤害
Mr. House faces criminal charges for battery against...
约翰·亨利·贾尔斯
John Henry Giles.
你居然袭击个坐轮椅的人
You beat up a guy in a wheelchair?
豪斯医生被指控  违背贾尔斯先生意愿
Dr. House is alleged to have forced a tube down
帮贾尔斯先生插喉管
Mr.Giles's throat against his will.
那是医疗用管  救人用的
A medical tube, saving his life.
豪斯医生  请让你的律师代表你发言
Dr. House, please let your attorney speak for you.
抱歉  法官大人  是我出格了
I'm sorry, Your Honor. I was way out of line.
也就是说  你的委托人强制给病人插喉管
So, uh, your client forced the patient into this position,
现在还想请求法院裁定
and now he wants a court order
继续强制病人接受治疗
to force the patient to stay that way.
没有那根管子
Without the tube,
贾尔斯先生很有可能就一命呜呼了
there's a high likelihood that Mr. Giles will die.
病人应该很清楚这点  他签了D.N.R.协议
Well, I assume the patient knows that. He had a D.N.R.
也正因此  你的委托人才被控犯罪  不是吗
That's why your client is facing criminal charges, right?
是的  但贾尔斯先生的死
Exactly. And Mr. Giles's death
也将触犯我委托人与其当庭对峙的权利
will violate my client's Sixth Amendment right.
你指他与原告对质的权利  很聪明
His right to face his accuser. That's clever, huh?
法官大人  根据联邦宾州豪斯顿的案例
Your Honor, in Commonwealth of Pennsylvania v. Hoselton,
施用于第三区时规定
the Third District ruled that
被告无权利用职务之便  违反...
a defendant may not use that status to rule against--
你为什么这么做
Why are you doing this?
-又不能免你牢狱之灾  -是不能
- It's not gonna keep you out of jail. - No.
即使你打赢官司  那份限制令
Even if you win, the restraining order
和伤害指控也不会撤销  有什么好处
and battery charge stay in place, so what have you gained?
时间
Time.
争取时间确诊吗  你都不能靠近他
To diagnose him? You can't get near him.
我也不想
I don't want to be near him.
有些医生有救世主情结
Well, some doctors have the messiah complex.
总想着拯救世界
They need to save the world.
你有魔方情结  总想着解决疑难杂症
You've got the Rubik's complex. You need to solve the puzzle.
你有完没完  还想对80年代时尚发表什么高论
Are you done? Or do you have more references to 1980s' fads?
我还想认真听庭审呢
I'm trying to listen to this.
那份D.N.R.协议有效性值得质疑
That D.N.R. May not be valid.
病人当时正因甲状腺功能失调
The patient was suffering from
情绪极度沮丧抑郁
depression brought on by a thyroid imbalance.
该D.N.R.协议签署时
The D.N.R. Order was witnessed...
有豪斯医生的手下  福曼医生作证
by Dr. House's own staff, a-- a-- a Dr. Foreman.
我那群手下都是白痴
My staff are idiots.
相信你肯定感同身受  法官大人
I'm sure you know what it's like, Your Honor.
坐下
Sit down.
D.N.R.协议的有效性  确实是个问题
The validity of the D.N.R. is a question of fact.
应该给豪斯医生一个机会
Dr. House should have the opportunity
收集足够证据  来证明自己的清白
to make his argument at a full trial.
而这位可怜的病人
And this poor guy has got to
在他收集足够证据前  只能继续接受治疗
stay on life support until we can schedule a trial.
-法官大人  -豪斯医生
- Your Honor-- - Dr. House,
再不坐下  我就告你蔑视法庭
I will hold you in contempt if you don't sit down.
我有个医学问题
I have a medical issue.
如果跟本案有关  你的律师...
If it pertains to this case, your attorney--
跟本案无关
It doesn't.
您的家族有心脏病史吗
Do you have any history of heart disease in your family?
-法官大人  -您的手指
- Your Honor! - Your fingers--
您的手指呈杵状  表示可能有心脏问题
They show signs of clubbing, which indicates a heart problem.
还记得巴特·吉亚玛提  和您一样  突然有天就猝死了
Remember Bart Giamatti? Same thing-- Just dropped dead one day.
-请及时去看医生  -他已经承认这与本案无关
- Please see your doctor. - He's admitted this isn't relevant.
能回到本案中来吗
Can we get back to the motion?
-当然  抱歉  -法官大人
- Of course. I-I'm sorry. - Your Honor,
病人决定自身治疗进程的权利
a person's right to control the treatment of their own body...
是理解本案的基础
is fundamental to understanding this case.
不论是联邦法院还是州立法院  大量的案例支持...
A long line of cases, both federal and state, stand to--
恭喜  法庭辩论让人印象深刻
Congratulations. Impressive legal argument.
-我昨晚看马特洛克(律政剧集)了  -还别说
- I watched Matlock last night. - Say no more.
我都没注意到法官的杵状指
I didn't notice any clubbing on the judge's fingers.
我也没有
Neither did I.
那你说的家族病史...
So the family history thing--
每个家族都有心脏病史
Every family has some history of heart disease.
还有精神病史
And mental illness.
-活检只显示有炎症  -给他用环磷酰胺
- Biopsy only shows inflammation. - Start him on Cytoxan.
就凭一点炎症  就确诊为韦氏病吗
You're diagnosing Wegener's based on a little inflammation?
不幸的是  我只是认为
Well, unfortunately, I think
虽然他自己不想做任何检测
we've exhausted all the tests we can do...
但我们已经尽了医生的本份
in our capacity as the doctors that
-能做的检测  都做过了  -你没有...
- he doesn't want doing tests on him. - Well, you don't--
如果用药后他能走了  说明用对药了
We'll know I'm right if he starts walking.
什么检测都不能做  还让我们继续治疗吗
We can't do any more tests, but you want me to treat him?
药在药房  病人就在重症监护室
Medicine's in the pharmacy. Patient's immobilized in the I.C.U.
简单的地理学问题
Sounds like a simple geography problem.
你是要我们冒着
Are you asking us to jeopardize
被吊销行医执照的危险给他治疗
our medical licenses for this treatment?
有什么能帮你的吗
Can I help you?
我是豪斯医生  我...
Uh, I'm Dr. House. I--
格雷戈是吧  我是马丁·汉密尔顿  约翰的医生
Greg, right? I'm Marty Hamilton, John Henry's doctor.
我们谈谈
We should talk.
感谢你像刚才那样给他用药
Appreciate any list of, uh, medications-- anything like that.
开始给他静脉滴注环磷酰胺了
I've started him on Cytoxan.
治疗韦氏病的  对吧
For Wegener's, right?
听我说  格雷戈
Look, Greg.
我查过你的资料
I checked you out, you know?
知道你是位好医生
I know you're a good doctor,
但你得承认  我这位医生也不赖
and you have to appreciate that I'm a good doctor too.
-为什么  -韦氏病的可能我早就考虑过了
- Why? - Wegener's is one of the first things I looked for.
活检和血检都是阴性的  相信你也一样
The biopsy and the blood test were negative, just like yours.
总会有错的  马丁
There's an error rate, Marty.
总要有释然的那一天
And there's a time to let go.
我会拔掉约翰·亨利的呼吸机
Look, I'm gonna take him off the ventilator,
他会逝去  正是他所希望的
and John Henry's going to die. He's accepted that.
汉密尔顿医生
Dr. Hamilton.
-你好  -你好
- How you doin'? - Hey, how you doin'?
抱歉  不该给你病人用免疫球蛋白的
Dr. Hamilton.I'm sorry.I should have never put your patient on I.V.I.G.
不是你的错  艾瑞克
It's not your fault, Eric.
-是我的错  艾瑞克  -我可没这么说
- No, it's mine, Eric. - That's not what I said.
洛杉矶那边大家都问你好
Everybody asks about you out in L.A.
那边现在怎么样
How's the old place doin'?
真是感人啊
Oh, this is wonderful.
两位先别真情流露  容我先说一句
But before you guys break out the oil, I should point out
你不能给他拔掉呼吸机  我有法庭禁令
that you can't pull the plug. I have a court order.
之前可能是  但...
You used to, but--
我有权跟原告当面对质  法官说的
I have the right to face my accuser. Judge said so.
除非没有原告  所有控告都已撤销
Not if no one's accusing you. All the charges have been dropped.
他根本不必死
He doesn't have to die.
不是韦氏病
It's not Wegener's.
如果是韦氏病  他的双肺根本撑不下去
If it's Wegener's, his lungs won't be able to handle it.
一旦拔下呼吸机  他就会死
Soon as they pull that plug, he'll die.
所以才说  拔掉呼吸机就像拔掉电源
That's why they call it "Pulling the plug".
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
-他仍在呼吸  -血氧浓度稳定
- He's still breathing. - His O2 sats are holding.
-血氧浓度靠自身稳定下来了  -他还在呼吸
- He's holding his own. - He's still breathing.
那不是韦氏病
It's not Wegener's.
又错了
Wrong again.
他情况稳定  单侧手臂失去知觉
He's stable, but one of his arms is now paralyzed.
真正的问题是  他为什么还活着
The real question is, why is he still alive?
会是因为他斗志顽强吗
Do you think he's just being stubborn?
因为你又错了  不是韦氏病
He's alive because you were wrong. It's not Wegener's.
对  最近好像总是这样
Yeah. Seem to be doing that a lot lately.
总是有人靠我犯错得以续命
People keep living because of my mistakes.
瘫痪病情的恶化
Progression of the paralysis
证明汉密尔顿基本上是对的  就是A.L.S.
pretty much confirmed Hamilton was right. It's A.L.S.
那得假定瘫痪的病情确实在恶化
Assuming this is a progression of his paralysis.
单侧手臂不能活动
He can't move his arm.
对  他手臂瘫痪了  对  他双腿也瘫痪了
Yes, his arm is paralyzed. Yes, his legs are paralyzed.
为什么大家都不约而同认为两者有联系
Why is everyone so gung ho to connect those two conditions?
你可以认为我错了  但没理由停止思考真正病因
You can think I'm wrong, but that's no reason to stop thinking.
这么想怎样  他不是我们的病人
How about this one? He's not our patient.
不  这理由不够好
Nope. Not good enough.
插喉管那次  他可能是因为血栓而致呼吸衰竭
He could've suffered a stroke when he was intubated.
血凝块  在瘫痪病人身上很常见
Well, blood clots are common in paralyzed patients.
-血流堵塞导致...  -原因我不感兴趣
- The inactivity causes-- - Not interested in why.
做个血管造影  找找有无栓塞
Let's get an M.R. Angiogram, check for an embolic stroke.
他不想由你治疗
He doesn't want you treating him.
-他们撤销了上诉  -对
- They dropped the court order. - Yeah,
那女孩也撤销了对科比的上诉
and that girl dropped the charges against Kobe.
并不意味着他就能打给她
Doesn't mean he should call her
-随时邀她去吃圣代  -说得好
- and see if she's free to get a sundae. - Good point.
但我现在能靠近他了
But I can go within 50 feet of him now.
需要的时候就找人呼我  随时都行
You need me, you have 'em page me. Anytime.
好
Okay.
-出去  -好  这样赶我也有道理
- Get out of here. - Sure. That makes sense.
你恨我救了你一命
You hate me for saving your life.
站在你的立场上看
Well, in fairness to your side,
你也是因为我差点死掉  所以...
you were also dying because of me, so--
你知道我不想被抢救
You knew I didn't want to be saved.
这正是有趣的地方
That's what's interesting.
你的甲状腺水平很低  但还不至于低到引起抑郁
Your thyroid was low, but not enough to cause depression.
所以你是来告诉我
So you came here to tell me that
即使我瘫痪了  还是可以听到鸟鸣
even if I can't walk, I can still hear the birds sing,
看到彩虹  感受到阳光拂过我脸庞
enjoy a rainbow, the feeling of sunshine on my face?
那些都很不错
Those things are fun.
我承认  活着就是受罪
Okay. Life sucks.
相比较而言  你更受罪
Your life sucks more than most.
虽然有更糟的  他们大多是自作孽不可活
It's not as bad as some, which is depressing all by itself.
帮我个忙
But do me a favor.
让我查出你到底是什么病
Just let me find out what's wrong with you.
到那时  你要是还想一死了之
Then if you still want to kill yourself,
我会助你一臂
I'll give you a hand.
-公平吗  -公平  当然
- That sound fair? - Yeah. Sure.
活受罪  只为了满足你的偏执
I'll stick around to indulge your obsession.
我已经完了  肺部没法运气
It's over. I lost my air.
那晚我去那间录音室...
The session the other night with those kids--
想试试看我还能否演奏  我做不到了
That was a test to see if I could still play. I can't.
你活着就为这个吗  做音乐
And that's all you are, a musician?
我只有这个  跟你一样
I got one thing, same as you.
真的
Really?
显然  你对我了解的比我对你的多
Well, apparently you know me better than I know you.
我知道你那条跛腿
I know that limp.
知道你为什么至今未婚
I know the empty ring finger.
知道你那近乎偏执的天性  那是你的隐秘
And that obsessive nature of yours-- That's a big secret.
你不惜冒着入狱失业的风险
You don't risk jail and your career
救一个一心求死之人
to save somebody who doesn't want to be saved...
除非你有一种信念  一种固执的信念
unless you got something-- anything-- one thing.
按部就班的人可以
The reason normal people
结婚生子  爱好广泛  等等等等
got wives and kids and hobbies-- whatever--
是因为他们缺少那种信念
That's because they ain't got that one thing that--
那种伤害至深又真挚隽永的执念
that hits 'em that hard and that true.
我有音乐  而你有这个
I got music. You got this--
一刻不停地占据你脑海
the thing you think about all the time,
让你不断地追寻着谜底
thing that keeps you south of normal.
正是这样  让我们更强  成为业内顶尖
Yeah. Makes us great. Makes us the best.
除此之外  我们一无所得
All we miss out on is everything else.
回家一室凄凉  没有爱人的亲近和小酌的闲趣
No woman waiting at home after work with the drink and the kiss.
孑然一身  形影相吊
That ain't gonna happen for us.
所以上帝创造了微波炉
That's why God made microwaves.
是啊
Yeah.
一旦没有音乐
But when it's over,
一切都结束了
It's over.
是啊
Yeah.
你这是干什么
What're you doin'?
对我来说  还没结束
It's not over for me.
要么你再报警  要么你就得跟我走
Either you're gonna call the cops again, or we're doing this.
你想死
You want to die,
躺在血管造影机里  也一样是死
you can do it just as easily inside an M.R.I. Machine.
等我回到洛杉矶
So when I go back to L.A.,
我还要做今年的权威讲座的报告
I'm doing the Dana lectures again this year.
-那可是种殊荣  -政治嘛
- That's quite an honor. - It's all political.
别谦虚了  你应得的
Don't be modest. You've earned it.
我的几项研究都取得很好成果
I got lucky on a couple studies I was doing.
总得有资格才行
It all sells tickets.
还记得去年的讲座吗
You remember last year's lectures, don't you?
我记得后来的雪茄吧
I remember the cigar bar afterwards.
参加这种会唯一的理由  雪茄和泳池美女
The only reason to attend the thing-- cigars and pool.
与豪斯医生共事愉快吗
You enjoy working with Dr. House?
说出来就大不敬了
Not the word I'd use.
我们都太专注工作  没时间享受人生  是吧
We work too hard not to enjoy ourselves, right?
-有交往对象吗  -可以这么说吧
- Mmm. You seeing anybody? - Kinda, sorta.
-是认真的吗  -我不知道  可能吧
- Serious? - I don't know. It could be.
你觉得她会喜欢洛杉矶吗
You think she'd, uh, enjoy L.A.?
汉密尔顿邀我过去工作
Hamilton offered me a job.
-你准备接受  -还没决定
- You gonna take it? - I haven't decided.
你已经有最精英的同事了
You already have the most prestigious fellowship.
当他合伙人
It's a partnership--
三倍工资  汽车津贴
Three times the money, car allowance,
还有差旅费  完整的退休计划
moving expense, pension plan,
加上跟那样一个懂得尊重
the chance to work for a guy who gives a
-别人想法的人共事  -那你为何不直接答应
- crap what people think. - Why didn't you just tell him yes?
-我还有合同在这  -对
- I made a commitment here. - Right.
豪斯会立马答应让你走的
House would let you out of it in a heartbeat.
或者不会  而是拿我开涮
Or he wouldn't, just to jerk me around.
要是你们  会接受吗
Would you guys have taken the job?
我不缺钱
Don't need the money.
我们跟你不同  我并不讨厌豪斯
We're not like you. I don't hate House.
你们真对他的所作所为  完全没意见
You guys really don't have a problem with him, with what he did?
他知道我们不赞成他的选择
He knows we disagree with his choice.
选择  奇斯  那可不是挑个水果  而是是非之分
Choice? Chase, it's not apples and oranges. It's right and wrong.
他一贯表现得毫不在乎  比如袭击了那人...
And he does it like he doesn't care. He assaults the guy...
却若无其事一般
and moves on to the next
继续做其他诊断
differential diagnosis like it's nothing.
你要他怎样  手足无措  折磨自己
What do you want from him? Hand-wringing? Torment?
-要他每晚都痛哭流涕吗  -对
- You want him to cry himself to sleep at night? - Yeah!
对  我只想知道他是把这当一回事的
Yeah, I want some clue that he knows it's a big deal.
能让他有所畏惧  郑重其事
That it scares him, that it matters.
那是什么
Whoa, whoa. What's that?
真的是血栓
It was a stroke.
-卡梅隆  干得好  -豪斯没错
- Well done, Cameron. - House called it.
手脚的瘫痪  是不相关的
The arm and legs are unrelated.
一竿子下去  总能打到几个枣
Oh, you make enough calls, one of them is bound to be right.
对  只是万分侥幸而已
Yeah. He's just a lucky, lucky guy.
我只是觉得
Listen, listen. I just think
学着谦虚点  对他没坏处
it wouldn't hurt him to learn a little humility.
诊断结果怎样
So what's the verdict?
是血栓  手臂瘫痪是因为血凝块
Embolus. The arm problem was caused by a clot.
施以组织纤溶酶原激活物  治血栓希望很大
There's a good chance we can bust the clot with T.P.A.
做吧  看他的手臂会怎样
Do it. See what happens to his arm.
在你脑部发现血栓
We found a blood clot in your brain.
想开始给你用肝素  那是种血液稀释剂
We'd like to start you on heparin. It's a blood thinner.
有何副作用
What are the side effects?
你的肺因瘫痪影响  已经受损严重
your lungs are kind of chewed up from the pneumonia.
-很有可能破损出血  -会流血
- Good chance there'll be an effusion. - Bleeding?
-流进肺里  -这是我们
- Into his lungs. - It's our best
治愈你手臂瘫痪的最好机会
chance to give you back the use of your arm.
以后都不能用肺运气  我还要手臂干嘛
I don't need my arm without my air.
-这样伤害是最小的  -不
- The damage would likely be minimal. - No.
他说了算
It's his call.
或者可以施行栓子切除术
Or we could do an embolectomy.
基本上  就是利用手术取出血栓
Basically, we go in and pull the clot out.
他拒绝用药  你们就建议他做开脑手术
He's saying no to drugs, and you're recommending brain surgery?
这样能避免肺部受损
Bypasses the risk to the lungs.
-要么治愈你的手臂  要么...  -要么我一命呜呼
- It'll either help your arm, or-- - Or it'll kill me.
站在你的立场  这是双赢的
From your point of view, it's a win-win.
好吧
Okay.
我们今天就安排手术
We'll set up the procedure for today.
现在进入你的颈动脉
We're in your carotid artery.
会沿着这里上行进入你大脑
This is gonna take us all the way up into your brain.
你还好吗
You all right?
是的
Yes.
血栓阻止了血液
The sludge is blocking the blood
流进你脑部控制手臂的区域
flow to the part of the brain that controls your arm.
手术完成  你还好吗
All done. You still okay?
是的
I think so.
我也不知道  我想...
I don't know. I guess...
可能正是因为汉密尔顿
it's just with Dr. Hamilton here,
让我意识到了不同的行事风格
I-I noticed a difference in styles.
你是说他很谦虚
His style involves humility?
我俩风格的另一个不同就是
Another difference in our styles--
道不道歉我觉得无所谓  你可以走了
I don't care much for apologies. You can go.
我说话的时候  不知道你就站在我身后  好吧
I didn't know you were standing there when I said that, okay?
-我那样实在太无礼了  -你觉得真正的谦虚
- It was completely rude. - Do you mean genuine humility,
是那种不断自我怀疑自我质疑的
you know, with all the self-doubt and the self-questioning,
还是汉密尔顿式的礼貌  盛气凌人表里不一的谦虚
or Hamilton's polite, patronizing, "Aw, shucks" Humility?
-你们都是很出色的医生  -谢谢
- You're both excellent doctors. - Thank you.
谦虚是种重要品质
And humility is an important quality,
尤其当你常常犯错的时候
especially if you're wrong a lot.
可你几乎每一步都在犯错
You've been wrong every step of the way.
当然  要是一直都对
'Course, when you're right,
那也没必要自我怀疑了  不是吗
self-doubt doesn't help anybody, does it?
该走了
We gotta go.
格雷戈  恭喜你
Congratulations, Greg.
恭喜  喜从何来  马丁
Congratulations. Why, Marty?
约翰醒了  手臂能动了
John woke up. He can use his arm.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我知道我们之间有分歧
Now, look, I know we've had our differences,
但只要某人做了好事
but I think when a person does something well,
还是该得到公认的
it ought to be recognized.
电话通的嘛
The phone works.
下次还想这么对我
Next time you want to make me feel
嘘寒问暖的时候  留言就行
all warm and fuzzy, leave a message.
别误会  我很为你高兴
Don't get me wrong. I'm overcome with joy.
-医生  -在
- Doc. - Yeah.
-什么  -你刚碰了我的腿
- What? - You just touched my leg.
怎么  还想再告我一次伤害罪
What, are you gonna charge me with assault again?
不是
No.
我感觉到了
I felt it.
他小腿以上  已经恢复知觉
He now has feeling all the way up to the calf.
药物起作用的方式就是这样
This is the way medicine evolved.
有时候病人情况好转
Patients sometimes get better.
我们却不知为何
You have no idea why,
除非知道什么在起作用  否则他们不会买账
but unless you give a reason, they won't pay you.
有没人注意过  是不是满月的影响
Anybody notice if there's a full moon?
你是说  他就这么自己好转了
You're saying he just spontaneously got better?
不  我是说我们得排除满月影响  然后继续
No. I'm saying, let's rule out the lunar god and go from there.
他用的某种药起了作用
Something he's on is working.
替代的药物起了作用  排除了A.L.S.可能
The enzyme replacement protocol is working, reversing the A.L.S.
这时机你不觉得很可疑吗
The timing doesn't seem suspicious to you?
你觉得豪斯医生也会这么认为吗
Do you think Dr. House'll see it that way,
认为是他的用药  起了作用
figure it's his medication doin' the job?
肯定会的
I'm sure he will.
是我们用的其中一种药
It's one of ours.
那怎么能确定到底是哪种呢
How do we figure out which drug is doing the trick?
简单  全部停用
Easy. We just stop all of them.
-可其中一种在起作用  -但其他的
- One of those drugs is helping him. - And the rest--
类固醇  抗生素  抗炎药
steroids, antibiotics,anti-inflammatories--
要是不同时停掉的话  是有毒的
They're toxic, if we leave him on all of them.
-可那样他就有能走了  -对  走去他自己葬礼
- He'll walk again. - Yeah. To his own funeral.
-但如果全部停药  他会恶化的  -对
- But if we stop everything, he'll get worse. - True.
所以得每次用回一种药
We'll add our medications back one at a time.
一旦出现好转  就能找到答案
When he gets better, we'll have our answer.
-要是他没好转呢  -那我们就麻烦了
- And if he doesn't get better? - Then we're in trouble.
当然没他麻烦大
Not as much as he is.
不过我猜你就是这个意思
But I suppose that was your point.
我猜你想让我说服
I assume you want me to convince
-汉密尔顿停止治疗  -我不在乎
- Hamilton to stop his treatments too. - Don't care.
你该知道  他至少用过五种药
At least five of the medications are a part of his protocol.
要是药管用
If his stuff was helping,
他几个月前就能打网球了
the guy would be playing tennis months ago.
肯定是我们的治疗在起作用
It's our round of treatment that's helping.
没错  可你却又要全部停药
Right. So that's what you'll stop.
不会超过15到20分钟
It shouldn't be more than 15 or 20 minutes.
所以你认为  如果他们不想治疗
So your philosophy is, if they don't want treatment,
哪怕强行灌药也要给他治
they get it shoved down their throat,
但如果有可能治愈的话
but if it might cure their paralysis,
-最好还是悠着点来  -没错
- whoa, we better slow down. - Yeah.
是的医生  我就爱这样
Yes, Doctor, I love it.
我之前的做法是听之任之
My old philosophy used to be live and let live.
可我越是研究下去
But I'm taking this needlepoint class,
越觉得任重而道远
and they gave us these really big pillows.
那你怎么处理同事关系的
What's your philosophy on employee relations?
那只是很小一块
That's a very tiny pillow.
很好  看来你很清楚自己在做什么
Great. It sounds like you know what you're doing.
格雷戈
Greg.
-能跟你谈谈吗  -能等到广告时间吗  马丁
- Can I have a word? - Can it wait for the commercial, Marty?
这位是我朋友吉米
Say hi to my friend Jimmy.
幸会
Pleasure.
你的诊断试验...
Your diagnostic trial--
说真的  还有5分钟就插播广告了
Seriously, commercial's in about five minutes.
实在太过危险
That's a dangerous game.
除非是坐浴缸里在看
Only if we're watching in the bathtub.
我需要确切知道
I need to know exactly
你给约翰·亨利用的什么药
what medications you were giving John Henry.
想都别想  如果福曼
Forget it. And if Foreman
私自告诉你约翰·亨利的用药记录
tells you what John Henry used to be on--
-你会解雇他吗  -不
- You're gonna fire him? - Nope.
我一定会让他做满两年合同期  才放他走
I'll make him live out every day of his two-year contract.
-福曼想跳槽吗  -还没
- Foreman asked to leave? - Not yet.
但你怎么知道我请他...
But how do you know I made him--
你虽然口蜜腹剑的  可不是白痴
You're a polite twit, but you're not an idiot.
我得知道  你到底给他停了什么药
I need to know what medications you've taken him off of.
等等  你不是白痴
Wait a second. You're not an idiot.
你得知道我到底停了什么药
You need to know what medications I've stopped...
是因为...
because--
情况恶化了
He's getting worse.
现在你还是我手下  跟我来
Right now you still work for me. Come on.
没有知觉  不能动弹
No feeling. No wiggling.
坏消息是约翰·亨利又回到了原点
Bad news is John Henry's back where he started.
好消息是汉密尔顿看上去灰头土脸的
Good news is Hamilton looks bad.
是啊  你输赢都没关系
Yeah, it's not whether you win or lose.
只要别人输了就好
It's whether the other guy loses.
我们给他用的第一个药是什么
What was the first thing we put him on?
类固醇  治疗肺炎
Steroids, for the pneumonia.
好  重新给他用  观察24小时看情况
Well, put him back on them. Give him 24 hours. See what happens.
他肺部状况很不好
His lungs aren't great.
类固醇很可能再次引起呼吸衰竭
They might cause another respiratory collapse.
希望不会  我可不怎么喜欢那律师
Sure hope not. I didn't much like that lawyer.
-做核磁共振  -已经做过  还做了血管造影
- And get an M.R.I. - He already got one, and an M.R.A.
很明显情况有变  再做一次
Well, obviously something is different now. Do it again.
奇斯负责扫描  卡梅隆给他用类固醇
Chase, take care of the scan. Cameron, put him on the steroids.
我们真该好好谈谈  是吧
We should probably talk, huh?
-薄切面  -扫描哪里
- Thin cuts. - What levels?
贯穿整个脊髓尾  跟上次一样
T-9 through the cauda equina, same as the last time.
你觉得豪斯会同意
You really think House would
-让福曼提前解约吗  -他没得选
- let Foreman out of his contract? - He has to.
不同意就表示他需要福曼
If he doesn't, he's telling Foreman he needs him.
豪斯可做不到
House can't handle that.
天哪
Oh, my God.
我查过他资料
I checked him out.
是位很不错的医生
He's a great doctor.
-你觉得他比我好吗  -这关系你的自我认同吗
- You think he's better than I am?  - This about your ego?
回答我的问题
Answer the question.
那不会改变我的自我认同
It's not gonna change how I think about myself.
但可能会影响我对你的看法
Might affect my opinion of you,
但也不该影响你的自我认同
but that shouldn't affect your opinion of yourself.
有点儿晕
Now I'm getting confused.
如果你认为他比我好
If you think he's a better doctor than I am,
你就该接受那份工作
then you should take the job.
否则  就再让他多请你吃两三次
Otherwise, you should get him to buy you
套老交情的美餐  然后婉拒他
two or three more nostalgic lunches and then politely decline.
就这么简单  我就该忍气吞声  忘记你的辱骂吗
It's that simple? I should just ignore the mockery and abuse?
-我哪有辱骂你  -你怎么没有
- Oh, how do I abuse you? - How do you not?
-我稍有犯错...  -我对你负有责任  这样怎么了
- If I make a mistake-- - I hold you accountable. So what?
汉密尔顿医生就会原谅
Dr. Hamilton forgives.
-他就能做到不再追究  -他才不是这样
- He's capable of moving on. - That is not what he does.
他的病人我差点搞砸
I screwed up his case.
-他却跟我说...  -他从没说过原谅你
- He told me-- - He never said you were forgiven.
我也在场  他只是说不是你的错
I was there. He said it wasn't your fault.
-所以呢  -所以那就是你的错
- So? - So, it was.
你冒了险  你做得很棒
You took a chance. You did something great.
你犯过错  可结果仍然很棒
You were wrong, but it was still great.
病人好转  你本就应该高兴
You should feel great that it was great.
病人恶化  你就该觉得糟糕
You should feel like crap that it was wrong.
那就是我跟他的不同
That's the difference between him and me.
他觉得医生就是份工作  该怎样就怎样
He thinks you do your job, and what will be will be.
我却认为当医生  一举一动都至关重要
I think that what I do and what you do matters.
他晚上能夜夜安眠  他不该这样
He sleeps better at night. He shouldn't.
是动静脉血管畸形
Arteriovenous malformation.
在硬膜内  压迫着他的脊柱
Intradural. Compressing his spine.
导致瘫痪
Causing his paralysis.
汉密尔顿怎么会连动静脉畸形都没查出来
How could Hamilton have missed an A.V.M.?
我们之前也没
Well, we missed it too,
因为之前并不在那里
'cause it wasn't there before.
你是说一夜之间长出来的
Are you saying it just grew overnight?
不
No.
本来就压迫在脊柱上  只是没拍出来
It was on the spine. It wasn't on the M.R.I.
-结构位置相同  -那里没有
- Same anatomic location. - It's not there.
-那里到底有什么  -什么都没有
- Well, what is there? - Nothing.
或者看上去什么都没有
Or something that looks like nothing.
-扫描时有背景噪音  是静电干扰  -是瘢痕组织  还是炎症
- Background noise. Static. - Scar tissue? Inflammation?
如果是炎症  类固醇早就治好了
If it's inflammation, the steroids would've shrunk it down.
考虑到是动静脉畸形
Revealing the A.V.M.,
肯定早就存在  只是被肿胀的发炎部位挡住了
which has always been there, hiding behind its own swelling.
类固醇消除了炎症  就能看出来了
We remove that, he'll walk again.
豪斯医生
Dr. House.
科拉在外面准备了豪华轿车来接我
Cora's meeting me outside with the limo.
我终于可以出院了
I'm bein' discharged.
五十块赌我能把你打到外面
Fifty bucks says I can beat you to the curb.
谢谢你没有放弃治疗
Thanks for stickin' with the case.
我又不会做别的
I can't do anything else.
能走路了  你倒容易取悦多了
You're much more easily amused when you can walk.
多奇怪啊
How bizarre.
要我猜  即使你腿还没坏的时候
I'm guessing that you weren't exactly Mr. Sunshine...
你也不是整天笑容满面的人
even before your leg got messed up.
我想给你这个
I want you to have this.
随便你高兴卖掉还是怎样
You can sell it if you want to.
只要你保证不吹
Just promise me you won't play it.
你那药都吃多少片了
How many of those pills you takin'?
我很痛苦
I'm in pain.
是啊
Yes.
谁不是呢
Aren't we all?
你那手杖哪里买的  真有专卖店吗
So where do you buy these things? Do they have cane stores?
别担心
Ah, don't worry about it.
没等你用坏一根  你就能跑步了
You'll be jogging before you need a second one.
明天见  艾瑞克
See you tomorrow, Eric.